Guide to the Mexico & Cuba Travel Ephemera Collection M1993
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Mexico & Cuba travel ephemera, 1884-1968
1937-1962
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M1993
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Small artificial collection of ephemera promoting travel and tourism in Mexico and Cuba.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections from 2012-2014.
Scope and Contents
Small collection of ephemera for American travelers to Mexico including brochures, pamphlets, tour guides, and postcards (both used and unused). There are also two 1939 World's Fair promotional booklets and an English-language magazine from Cuba.
Mexico -- Description and travel.; Cuba -- Description and travel
- Mario Bucovich - Mexico (prints), circa 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Vamos a Mexico (SPRR), 1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous travel brochures (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Luis Covarrubias - Regional Dances of Mexico (Eugenio Fischgrund), circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Before That Trip to the Moon, Visit Mexico! Now! (Century 21 Exposition/Eco Publicistas), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Answers to Your Questions About Mexico - The Friendly Land (Century 21 Exposition/Mexican Government Tourism Department), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Make Friends With Mexico (American Airlines), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Scope and Contents
  Transferred from Hopkins Transportation Collection.
- T.S. Power - Mexico In Your Own Car (Pan American Tourist Bureau), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Henry W. Taylor - Mexican Journeys [tour advertising brochure], 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mexico: The Faraway Land Nearby (Mexican Tourist Association) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- James W. Steele - To Mexico By Palace Car (Chicago: Jansen, McClurg & Co.), 1884 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- David S. Oakes - Sunshine Over The Border (Reprinted by the Mexican Tourist Association), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Souvenir of Tijuana, Mexico [posed photograph of five tourists in somberos] (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Postcards, circa 1906-1968 (Box 1, Folders 14-16)
  Some are used and postmarked, others are blank. Many are real photograph postcards.
- Visit Cuba at the World's Fair (Carasa & Co.), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cuba (Cuban Tourist Commission), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Times of Cuba, August 1916 (Box 1, Folder 19)